Guide to the Ken White Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Ken White Collection
1964-1986
AOB 38
Yale University Arts Library
1
(3 boxes)
The Ken White Collection documents the graphic design career of Ken White from 1964 to 1985 through examples of publications and ephemera he designed for specific clients. White worked for a variety of clients, including IBM, Better Homes and Gardens, and the Phoenix Art Museum.
White, Ken
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jo Ann White, 1986.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Ken White was born in Kansas City, MO, in 1935. He majored in commercial art at the University of Kansas, but left to serve in the Marines from 1956-58. After, he attended the Kansas City Art Institute and received his BFA in 1960. In 1959 he married Jo Ann Johnson. They had a daughter, Wendy, in 1960, and a son, Kenneth, in 1964. White worked for the Meredith Publishing Company from 1960-65. He then attended the MFA program at Yale University, receiving his degree in 1967. He then worked for IBM until 1981, and various other companies, until he became the Associate Professor of Graphic Design at Arizona State University in 1984. He died in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The Ken White Collection documents the graphic design career of Ken White from 1964 to 1985 through examples of publications and ephemera he designed for specific clients. White worked for a variety of clients, including IBM, Better Homes and Gardens, and the Phoenix Art Museum.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Clients, 1964-1985. II. Personal, 1986.
Commercial art -- United States -- 20th Century; Graphic arts; Printed ephemera
- Clients, Series I
  Arrangement
  Listed in alphabetical order by client name.
  - Better Homes and Gardens, 1964 undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    See also Oversize Box 3.
  - IBM, 1972-1975 undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - IBM Austin, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - IBM Boulder, 1967 1971 undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - IBM Boulder, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - IBM Lexington (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - IBM Professional College Recruiting (Boulder, CO), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - IBM Santa Teresa Laboratory, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - IBM Santa Teresa Laboratory, 1979 undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - IBM Tucson Dedication 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ITT Programming, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Journal of Creative Behavior, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New York Insurance Exchange, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - SEK, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Triglyph, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Personal, Series II
  - Biography by Jo Ann White, January 21, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Oversize
  - Better Homes and Gardens, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - IBM, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - IBM Tucson Dedication 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)